Scientists Collection 1563-1973 Mss.509.L56
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. American-Russian Scientific Correspondence, 1789-1910; 0.25 lin. feet 1 upright box.
  - Letter to Salemann, Karl Germanovich, 1849-1916, 1903 Jun. 15; 509 L56.m; Jackson, Abraham Valentine Wiliams, 1862-1937
    Rostow, Photo.of A.L.S.on postal card. 1p.and add. (see Letters of scientists. Moscow...) Enjoyed his stay in Persia and outlines his voyage to New York.
  - Letter to Backlund, Johann Oscar, 1846-, 1903 Jun.; 509 L56.m; Boss, Lewis, 1846-1912
    Photo.of Typed L.S. 8p. (see Letters of scientists. Moscow...) Suggestions of plans for a southern hemisphere observatory for mapping the sky. Astronomical research.
  - Letter to Backlund, Johann Oscar, 1846-, 1903 Jul. 7; 509 L56.m; Boss, Lewis, 1846-1912
    Albany, N.Y., Photo. of Typed L.S. 3p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Questions concerning the establishment of an observatory in the southern hemisphere.
  - Letter to Backlund, Johann Oscar, 1846-, 1903 Jul. 30; 509 L56.m; Abbe, Cleveland, 1838-1916
    Washington, Photo.of A.L.S. 1p. (see Letters of scientists. Moscow...) Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to American Philosophical Society, 1906 Apr. 1; 509 L56.m; Académie imperiale des sciences de St. Petersbourg.
    photo.of L.S.: Constantin. 1p. In French. (see Letters of scientists. Moscow...) Congratulations on 200th anniversary of B.Franklin.
  - Letter to Salemann, Karl Germanovich, 1849-1916, 1908 Jan. 1; 509 L56.m; Jackson, Abraham Valentine Wiliams, 1862-1937
    Yonkers, New York, Photo.of A.L.S. 2p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Thanks for his publication on Persian and praises it highly.
  - Letter to Backlund, Johann Oscar, 1846-, 1908 Mar. 31; 509 L56.m; Abbe, Cleveland, 1838-1916
    Washington, Photo.of A.L.S. 1p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Thanks for his publications. Concerning astronomical problems.
  - Letter to Backlund, Johann Oscar, 1846-, 1909 Apr. 6; 509 L56.m; Boss, Lewis, 1846-1912
    San Luis, Argentina, Photo.of A.L.S. 2p. (see Letters of scientists. Moscow...) Is working on establishing a southern hemisphere observatory.
  - Letter to Backlund, Johann Oscar, 1846-, 1909 Jul. 1; 509 L56.m; Boss, Lewis, 1846-1912
    Berlin, Photo.of A.L.S. 4p. (see Letters of scientists. Moscow...) Astronomy and astronomical problems.
  - Letter to Backlund, Johann Oscar, 1846-, 1910 Jul. 16; 509 L56.m; Boss, Lewis, 1846-1912
    Albany, N.Y., Photo of A.L.S. 4p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Enjoyed their visit. Astronomy.
  - Letter to Salemann, Karl Germanovich, 1849-1916, 1910 Aug. 16; 509 L56.m; Jackson, Abraham Valentine Wiliams, 1862-1937
    New York, Photo.of A.L.S. 2p.and photo.of newspaper clipping. (see Letters of scientists Moscow...) Welcomes him to New York.
  - Letter to Backlund, Johann Oscar, 1846-, 1910 Sep. 13; 509 L56.m; Boss, Lewis, 1846-1912
    Albany, N.Y., Photo.of A.L.S. 2p, (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Will forward mail to Tokyo. Enjoyed his visit.
  - Letter to Backlund, Johann Oscar, 1846-, 1910 Dec. 25; 509 L56.m; Boss, Lewis, 1846-1912
    Photo.of A.L.S.on postal card. 1p.snd add. (see Letters of scientists. Moscow...) Christmas greetings.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; 509 L56.m; Clarke, Alexander Ross, 1828-1914
    Photo.of A.L.S. 3p. Incomplete. (see Letters of scientists. Moscow...) Hopes they can use the standard for some time. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; 509 L56.m; Clarke, Alexander Ross, 1828-1914
    Southampton, Photo.of A.L.S. 4p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) June 8. Will sends bars to Berlin. Asks for news of improved instruments for astronomical observations, pendulums, etc.
- Series III. Physicists' Correspondence, 1786-1961; 0.25 lin. feet 1 upright box.; Max Planck is a particularly well-represented recipient and author of letters. Correspondents include Hans Thacher Clarke, Gerard Peter Kuiper, and Raymond John Seeger.
  Correspondence and other materials relating primarily to Max Planck, Wilhelm Wien, and Arnold Sommerfeld. Some material formerly organized as Max Planck correspondence, 1919-1948, Mss.509.L56.p.
  Materials presented by Hans T. Clarke, Nov. 1964 (1964 2512ms) and purchased at Stargardt sale, Nov. 24-5, 1964 (1964 2907ms).
  Background note
  Physicist Max Planck authored the quantum theory.
  Barton, Henry Askew, 1898-1983; Clarke, Frieda; Clarke, Hans Thacher, 1887-1972; Kuiper, Gerard Peter, 1905-; Planck, Max, 1858-1947; Richards, Alfred N. (Alfred Newton), 1876-1966; Seeger, Raymond John, 1906-; Physics; Science
  - Table of contents, L56.p, Stargardt
  - Table of contents, L56.p, Clarke
  - Letter to ---, 1786 Apr. 20; 509 L56.p; 9x7-1/4; Forster, Johann Reinhold, 1729-1798
    Halle, A.L. 5p. Describes flora and fauna located on trip with Captain Cook. Refers to various important scientists.
  - Letter to Dr. Sauppe, Göttingen, 1887 Oct. 26; 509 L56.p; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Weber, Wilhelm, 1804-1891
    Göttingen, A.L.S. 1p.and add.envelope. In German. Is giving up membership in the K.Gesellschaft der Wissenschaften, since he is unable to participate in scientific or business activities.
  - Letter to [Wilhelm Wien], 1895-1896; 509 L56.p; 7x4-1/2; Wien, Max, 1866-1938
    [Winter]. A.L.S. 4p. In German. Concerning Röntgen's audience with Wilhelm II, with experiments. Details on how to duplicate the experiment. Details on the audience.
  - Letter to W[ilhelm] Wien, 1896 Jan. 16; 509 L56.p; 7x4-1/2; Planck, Max, 1858-1947
    Berlin, A.L.S. 2p. In German. Asks if he would like to edit the planned new edition of Mechanik, by G.R.Kirchhoff.
  - Letter to [Wilhelm Wien], 1901 June 19; 509 L56.p; 7x4-1/2; Wien, Max, 1866-1938
    Aachen, A.L.S. 4p. In German. Concerning work at the Polytechnikum. Mentions the laboratories and his experiments.
  - New Year's Greetings, to Herrn & Frau Professor Dr. W. Wien, Würzburg, 1904 Dec. 31; 509 L56.p; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Röntgen, Wilhelm Conrad, 1845-1923
    Picture postal card, signed. 1p.and add. In German.
  - Letter to Dr. Laub, Wurzburg, 1907 Sept. 7; 509 L56.p; 10-1/4x6-1/2; Wien, W. (Wilhelm), 1864-1928
    A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. In German. Concerning objections of von Laue on Laub's work. Asks him to check against these objections.
  - Letter to [Arnold] Sommerfeld, 1910 Jan. 24; 509 L56.p; 7x4-1/2; Rayleigh, John William Strutt, Baron, 1842-1919
    Witham, Essex, A.L.S. 2p. Comments on his treatment of Kelvin's problem and asks if he has carried it further.
  - Letter to [Wilhelm Wien], 1911 Nov. 18; 509 L56.p; 6-3/4x5; Wien, Max, 1866-1938
    Jena, A.L.S. 4p. In German. On the Nobel prize for Wien and Planck. Mentions Solvay Congress and the "Curie scandel" Personal news.
  - Letter to [Wilhelm Wien], 1913 Oct. 6; 509 L56.p; 7x5-1/4; Röntgen, Wilhelm Conrad, 1845-1923
    A.L.S. 1p. In German. Letter of condolence to Wien, at the death of his father-in-law.
  - Letter to J. Laub, Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1916 March 7; 509 L56.p; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Wien, W. (Wilhelm), 1864-1928
    Würzburg, Typed L.S.on postal card. 1p.and add. In German. Received two photographic plates but the manuscript is missing. Suggests differing routes for each copy in the future.
  - Letter to [Arnold Sommerfeld], 1917 June 18; 509 L56.p; 9x5-3/4; Rubens, Heinrich, 1865-1922
    Berlin, A.L.S. 2p. In German. Thanks for his letter and the articles. Concerning a diamond which he thinks belongs to the Berliner Institut.
  - Letter to Mrs. Frieda [Planck] Clarke, Rochester, N.Y., 1919 Dec. 23; 509 L56.p; 7x4-1/2; Planck, Max, 1858-1947
    Berlin, A.L.S. 4p.and envelope addressed. In German. Thanks for congratulations. Talks about death of his daughter, Emma.
  - Letter to [Max Planck], 1921 Nov. 16; 509 L56.p; 11x8-1/2; Wien, W. (Wilhelm), 1864-1928
    Munich, A.L.S. 2p. In German. On his and Planck's view of Einstein's theory.
  - Letter to [Max Planck], 1923 Jan. 24; 509 L56.p; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Wien, W. (Wilhelm), 1864-1928
    Munich, A.L.S. 7p. In German. Concerning the new Physikalisches Institut and his intended position there.
  - Letter to [Max Planck], 1923 Jan. 27; 509 L56.p; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Wien, W. (Wilhelm), 1864-1928
    Munich, A.L.S. 5p. In German. Concerning the location, inventory and positions of the new physical institute.
  - Letter to [Max Planck], 1923 Feb. 19; 509 L56.p; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Wien, W. (Wilhelm), 1864-1928
    Munich, A.L.S. 3p. In German. Concerning the planned physical institute and the possibility of his position there.
  - Letter to [Max] Planck, Berlin, 1923 March 24; 509 L56.p; 5-3/4x3-1/2; Wien, W. (Wilhelm), 1864-1928
    Munich, A.L.S.on postal card. 2p.,add. In German. Concerning erecting a new physical institute.
  - Letter to [Max Planck], 1923 March 27; 509 L56.p; 11-1/2x9; Wien, W. (Wilhelm), 1864-1928
    Munich, A.L.S. 2p. In German. Received note about optical resonance and will print it. Plans failed for the physical institute, because no suitable rooms were available.
  - Letter to [Max Planck], 1923 June 30; 509 L56.p; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Wien, W. (Wilhelm), 1864-1928
    Munich, A.L.S. 4p. In German. Concerning the physical institutes in Munich and Berlin.
  - Letter to [Wilhelm Wien], 1924 Jan. 10; 509 L56.p; 7x6; Lenard, Philipp, 1862-1947
    Heidelberg, A.L.S. 4p. In German. Birthday greetings (60th). Praises the "Annalen." Will send article for the annals on surface tension.
  - Letter to [Wilhelm Wien], 1924 Jan. 11; 509 L56.p; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Planck, Max, 1858-1947
    A.L.S. 2p. In German. (see Letters of Scientists - Physicists.) Birthday greetings on his 60th birthday. News of his son's marriage.
  - Letter to [Max Planck], 1924 Oct. 3; 509 L56.p; 11-1/2x8-3/4; Wien, W. (Wilhelm), 1858-1947
    A.L.S. 1p. In German. On vacation. Encloses article [article wanting]. Mentions meeting of Physikalische Gesellschaft in Innsbruck.
  - Letter to [Max Planck], 1924 Nov. 16; 509 L56.p; 11-1/2x8-3/4; Wien, W. (Wilhelm), 1864-1928
    Munich, A.L.S. 1p. In German. Concerning Paschen and his position and work at the institute.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Frieda Planck Clarke], 1925 May 2; 509 L56.p; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Planck, Max, 1858-1947
    Berlin, A.L.S. 4p. In German. Thanks for birthday greetings and pictures. Will visit Munich for opening of the Deutsche Museum. Household matters, friends, failure of plans for moving.
  - Letter to [Max Planck], 1925 June 17; 509 L56.p; 11x9; Wien, W. (Wilhelm), 1864-1928
    A.L.S. 1p. In German. Enclosing a work by Schrödinger. Has moved into a new home.
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, Munich, 1926 Oct. 26; 509 L56.p; 8x6-1/4; Compton, K. T. (Karl Taylor), 1887-1954
    Zürich, A.L.S. 2p. Wishes to use his library to prepare a report for the National Research Council on "Discharge of Electricity through Gases."
  - Letter to K. Sellmayer, 1927 May 10; 509 L56.p; 11x8-3/4; Hevesy, Georg von, 1885-1966
    Freiburg, A.L.S. 1p. In German. Orders "Grundserie..."
  - Letter to [Max Planck], 1927 Oct. 18; 509 L56.p; 11x8-1/2; Wien, W. (Wilhelm), 1864-1928
    Munich, A.L.S. 1p. In German. Regrets that Planck could not visit Kissingen. Concerning his latest travels and his work at the institute.
  - Letter to [Max Planck], 1928 Feb. 5; 509 L56.p; 11x8-1/2; Wien, W. (Wilhelm), 1864-1928
    Munich, A.L.S. 4p. In German. Will stay at his house, if he comes to Berlin but is uncertain. Concerning manuscripts: physicists becoming so specialized they publish in special journals.
  - Letter to [Max Planck], 1928 March 19; 509 L56.p; 11x8-1/2; Wien, W. (Wilhelm), 1864-1928
    Munich, A.L.S. 1p. In German. Encloses an article sent to him. Mentions his stay in Berlin. [Article wanting].
  - Letter to [Sir Chandrasekhara Venkata Raman], 1929 June?; 509 L56.p; 10-1/2x8; Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1868-1951
    A.L.in pencil. 1p. Draft. In German. Sends correction for lectures. Thanks for trouble over publication. Parcel from India not yet arrived. Friendly letter. On same sheet as Raman to Sommerfeld; May 5, 1929.
  - Letter to [Arnold] Sommerfeld, 1929 May 5; 509 L56.p; 10-1/2x8; Raman, Chandrasekhara Venkata, Sir, 1888-1970
    Calcutta Typed L.S. 1p. Forwards proofs of his Calcutta lectures. On same sheet is draft of Sommerfeld's reply; [June?, 1929].
  - Letter to A[rnold] Sommerfeld, Munich, 1930 Jan. 13; 509 L56.p; 11x8-1/2; Compton, K. T. (Karl Taylor), 1887-1954
    Princeton, Typed L.S. 1p. Thanks him for correcting an error in an article by Dr. Harnwell.
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, Munich, 1930 Jan. 24; 509 L56.p; 11x8-1/2; Compton, Arthur Holly, 1892-1962
    Chicago, Typed L.S. 1p. Asks if Statuss may study with him and states the man's abilities.
  - Letter to ----, 1931 April 17; 509 L56.p; 7x5-3/4; Planck, Max, 1858-1947
    Berlin, A.L.S. 1p. In German. Encloses a letter of recommendation to Pegram. [Enclosure wanted.]
  - Letter to [Arnold] Sommerfeld, 1932 Jan. 14; 509 L56.p; 11x8-3/4; Debye, Peter J. W. (Peter Josef William), 1884-
    Leipzig, Typed L.S. 1p. In German. Friendly letter, asking for another letter for request to the Rockefeller Foundation for grant.
  - Letter to [Arnold] Sommerfeld, Munich, 1933 Nov. 25; 509 L56.p; 4x6; Debye, Peter J. W. (Peter Josef William), 1884-
    Berlin, A.L.S.on postal card. 1p.and add. In German. Asks for an invitation for Max von Angerer.
  - Letter to [Arnold] Sommerfeld, 1935 Jan. 25; 509 L56.p; 10-1/4x8-1/4; Bragg, William Henry, Sir, 1862-1942
    London, Typed L.S. 1p. Asks if he knows of any traces of Rumford's works in Munich. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Mr. and Mrs. Hans [Clarke], 1936 May 17; 509 L56.p; 7x5-1/2; Planck, Max, 1858-1947
    A.L.S. 4p. In German. Thanks for birthday greetings. Cannot visit them. Itemizes lecture ture. Will represent Berliner Akademie der Wissenschaften at the Univ. of London's celebration. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Frieda Planck Clarke], 1937 May 17; 509 L56.p; 7x6; Planck, Max, 1858-1947
    Berlin, A.L.S. 2p. In German. Thanks for birthday letter. Concerning his travels and plans for travelling. Still working for Kaiser-Wilhelm-Gesell-schaft and Akademie der Wissesschaften.
  - Letter to Frau Hofrat Lampa, Vienna, 1938 Jan. 31; 509 L56.p; 7x6; Planck, Max, 1858-1947
    Berlin, A.L.S. 2p.and add.envelope. In German. Letter of condolence to the widow of Anton Lamps.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Frieda Planck Clarke], 1939 May 12; 509 L56.p; 7x6; Planck, Max, 1858-1947
    Berlin, A.L.S. 2p. In German. Thanks for birthday letter. His recent travels. News of family.
  - Letter to Mr. and Mrs. Hans Thacher Clarke, New York, 1939 Oct. 23; 509 L56.p; 8-1/4x6; Planck, Max, 1858-1947
    Berlin, A.L.S. 4p.and add.envelope. In German. Concerning the Clarke's 25th wedding anniversary. Travels in Europe. Family news.
  - Letter to Hans [Thacher] Clarke, New York, 1940 March 9; 509 L56.p; 4-1/4x6; Planck, Max, 1858-1947
    Berlin, A.L.S.on postal card. 1p. In German. Thanks for Christmas greetings and picture. News of family.
  - Letter to Frau Wien, 1944 Jan. 3; 509 L56.p; 8-1/4x6; Planck, Max, 1858-1947
    Magdeburg, A.L.S. 2p. In German. To the widow of Wilhelm Wien, about the war. Air raids in Kassel.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Frieda Planck Clarke], 1945 Sept. 26; 509 L56.p; 10-3/4x8; Seidel, Mrs. Planck
    Goettingen, Typed L. 1p. Extract. (see Letters of scientists - Physicists) Concerning Max Planck.
  - Letter to H[ans] T. Clark[e], New York, 1945 Nov. 17; 509 L56.p; 11x8-1/2; Kuiper, Gerard Peter, 1905-
    Williams Bay, Wis., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerning Max Planck.
  - Letter to G[erard] P. Kuiper, Williams Bay, Wisc., 1945 Nov. 19; 509 L56.p; 11x8-1/2; Clarke, Hans Thacher, 1887-1972
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. Thanks for news of Max Planck.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Frieda Planck] H. T. Clarke-Planck, New York, 1945 Nov. 22; 509 L56.p; 11x8-1/2; Seeger, Raymond John, 1906-
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p.and add.envelope. Concerning Max Planck and encloses letter from him.
  - Letter to Henry A. Barton, New York, 1945 Dec. 27; 509 L56.p; 11x8-1/2; Clarke, Hans Thacher, 1887-1972
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. Forwards Max Planck material.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Frieda Planck Clarke], 1946 July 21; 509 L56.p; 8x5; Planck?, Mrs. Marga
    London, A.L.S. 10. In German. Planck's memory failing. Difficult living conditions. Political conditions. Family affairs. Refugees.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Frieda Planck Clarke], 1946 Oct. 13; 509 L56.p; 8-1/2x6; Planck?, Mrs. Marga
    A.L.S. 4p. In German. Health of Hans and Frieda Clarke. Planck's memory failing. Family news and news of friends.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Frieda Clarke], 1947 Jan. 7; 509 L56.p; 6x6; Planck, Max, 1858-1947
    A.L.S. 2p. In German. Looking forward to her visit. Wishes to remain in Göttingen (city of his ancestors) until he dies.
  - Letter to Mrs. Frieda Planck Clarke, New York, 1948 April 14; 509 L56.p; 11x8-1/2; Richards, Alfred N. (Alfred Newton), 1876-1966
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p.and enclosure. Sends her the National Academy of Sciences statement in memory of Max Planck
  - Die Freiheit der Atome, [1961]; 509 L56.p; 11x8-1/2; Jordan, Pascual, 1902-1980
    A.D. 11p. In German. Religion and science, especially since the new atomic theories.
  - "Aerology. (Text of Maguire) Weather elements and their Observation.", undated; 509 L56.p; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Hess, Victor Franz, 1883-
    A. D. 4p.
  - Concerning cancer in mice caused by radioactive iron., undated; 509 L56.p; 11-1/2x8-1/2; Hevesy, Georg von, 1885-1966
    Typed D.31p. Incomplete.
- Series IV. Enrico Fermi Correspondence, 1917-1926, 1958; 0.25 lin. feet 1 upright box.; These are letters and postcards on scientific and personal matters, with a long letter (1958) about Fermi's career from Adolfo Amidei to Emilio Segrè.; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  Predominately written in Italian. Formerly comprised the Enrico Fermi letters, 1918-1926, to Enrico Perisco, Mss.509.L56.p1. Fermi's letters are numbered (presumably by Persico or Segrè).
  Existence and Location of Copies note
  All material published in English in Segrè's biography of Fermi.
  Enrico Fermi was a physicist.
  Presented by Emilio Segrè and accessioned, 1965.
  Location of originals unknown.
  Amidei, Adolfo; Perisco, Enrico; Segrè, Emilio Gino, 1905-1989; Physicists.; Physics
  - Postcard to Enrico Persico, 1917 May 7; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
    Includes a sketch of a barometer. Appears to be a fragment.
  - Postcard to Enrico Persico, 1918 Aug. 18; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
    On same sheet as 9 Dec. 1918, Fermi to Persico.
  - Postcard to Enrico Persico, 1918 Dec. 9; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
    On same sheet as 18 Aug. 1918, Fermi to Persico.
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1919 Feb. 12; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1919 Aug. 6; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1919 Dec. 11; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1920 Jan. 30; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1920 May 30; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1920 ? 29; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Postcard to Enrico Perisco, 1921 Nov. 24; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1922 Jan. 25; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1922 Mar. 18; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
    Includes 20 Mar. postscript.
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1922 May 25; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1922 Jun. 2; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1922 Jun. 8; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1922 Aug. 28; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1923 Mar. 31; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Postcard to Enrico Perisco, 1923 Apr. 21; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
    On same sheet as 26 July 1924, Fermi to Persico.
  - Postcard to Enrico Perisco, 1924 Jul. 26; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
    On same sheet as 21 April 1923, Fermi to Persico.
  - Postcard to Enrico Perisco, 1924 Sept. 13; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1925 May 22; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1925 Jun. 2; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1925 Sep. 23; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1925 Oct. 1; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Postcard to Enrico Perisco, 1925 Oct. 15; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1926 May 17; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1926 Jun. 29; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Letter to Enrico Perisco, 1926 Sep. 7; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
  - Letter to Emilio Segrè, 1958 Nov. 25; Amidei, Adolfo
    Concerning Enrico Fermi.